A woman of faith? An expert? Maybe even a sister. Or oppressed, brainwashed, a terrorist. Or just an airport security line delay. That one's actually true. (Laughter) If some of your perceptions were negative, I don't really blame you. That's just how the media has been portraying people who look like me. One study found that 80 percent of news coverage about Islam and Muslims is negative. And studies show that Americans say that most don't know a Muslim. I guess people don't talk to their Uber drivers. (Laughter) Well, for those of you who have never met a Muslim, it's great to meet you. Let me tell you who I am. I'm a mom, a coffee lover -- double espresso, cream on the side. I'm an introvert. I'm a wannabe fitness fanatic. And I'm a practicing, spiritual Muslim. But not like Lady Gaga says, because baby, I wasn't born this way. It was a choice. When I was 17, I decided to come out. No, not as a gay person like some of my friends, but as a Muslim, and decided to start wearing the hijab, my head covering. My feminist friends were aghast: "Why are you oppressing yourself?" The funny thing was, it was actually at that time a feminist declaration of independence from the pressure I felt as a 17-year-old, to conform to a perfect and unattainable standard of beauty. I didn't just passively accept the faith of my parents. I wrestled with the Quran. I read and reflected and questioned and doubted and, ultimately, believed. My relationship with God -- it was not love at first sight. It was a trust and a slow surrender that deepened with every reading of the Quran. Its rhythmic beauty sometimes moves me to tears. I see myself in it. I feel that God knows me. Have you ever felt like someone sees you, completely understands you and yet loves you anyway? That's how it feels. And so later, I got married, and like all good Egyptians, started my career as an engineer. (Laughter) I later had a child, after getting married, and I was living essentially the Egyptian-American dream. And then that terrible morning of September, 2001. I think a lot of you probably remember exactly where you were that morning. I was sitting in my kitchen finishing breakfast, and I look up on the screen and see the words "Breaking News." There was smoke, airplanes flying into buildings, people jumping out of buildings. What was this? An accident? A malfunction? My shock quickly turned to outrage. Who would do this? And I switch the channel and I hear, "... Muslim terrorist ...," "... in the name of Islam ...," "... Middle-Eastern descent ...," "... jihad ...," "... we should bomb Mecca." Oh my God. Not only had my country been attacked, but in a flash, somebody else's actions had turned me from a citizen to a suspect. That same day, we had to drive across Middle America to move to a new city to start grad school. And I remember sitting in the passenger seat as we drove in silence, crouched as low as I could go in my seat, for the first time in my life, afraid for anyone to know I was a Muslim. We moved into our apartment that night in a new town in what felt like a completely different world. And then I was hearing and seeing and reading warnings from national Muslim organizations saying things like, "Be alert," "Be aware," "Stay in well-lit areas," "Don't congregate." I stayed inside all week. And then it was Friday that same week, the day that Muslims congregate for worship. And again the warnings were, "Don't go that first Friday, it could be a target." And I was watching the news, wall-to-wall coverage. Emotions were so raw, understandably, and I was also hearing about attacks on Muslims, or people who were perceived to be Muslim, being pulled out and beaten in the street. Mosques were actually firebombed. And I thought, we should just stay home. And yet, something didn't feel right. Because those people who attacked our country attacked our country. I get it that people were angry at the terrorists. Guess what? So was I. And so to have to explain yourself all the time isn't easy. I don't mind questions. I love questions. It's the accusations that are tough. Today we hear people actually saying things like, "There's a problem in this country, and it's called Muslims. When are we going to get rid of them?" So, some people want to ban Muslims and close down mosques. They talk about my community kind of like we're a tumor in the body of America. And the only question is, are we malignant or benign? You know, a malignant tumor you extract altogether, and a benign tumor you just keep under surveillance. The choices don't make sense, because it's the wrong question. Muslims, like all other Americans, aren't a tumor in the body of America, we're a vital organ. (Applause) Thank you. Muslims are inventors and teachers, first responders and Olympic athletes. Now, is closing down mosques going to make America safer? It might free up some parking spots, but it will not end terrorism. Going to a mosque regularly is actually linked to having more tolerant views of people of other faiths and greater civic engagement. And as one police chief in the Washington, DC area recently told me, people don't actually get radicalized at mosques. They get radicalized in their basement or bedroom, in front of a computer. And what you find about the radicalization process is it starts online, but the first thing that happens is the person gets cut off from their community, from even their family, so that the extremist group can brainwash them into believing that they, the terrorists, are the true Muslims, and everyone else who abhors their behavior and ideology are sellouts or apostates. So if we want to prevent radicalization, we have to keep people going to the mosque. Now, some will still argue Islam is a violent religion. After all, a group like ISIS bases its brutality on the Quran. Now, as a Muslim, as a mother, as a human being, I think we need to do everything we can to stop a group like ISIS. But we would be giving in to their narrative if we cast them as representatives of a faith of 1.6 billion people. (Applause) Thank you. ISIS has as much to do with Islam as the Ku Klux Klan has to do with Christianity. (Applause) Both groups claim to base their ideology on their holy book. But when you look at them, they're not motivated by what they read in their holy book. It's their brutality that makes them read these things into the scripture. Recently, a prominent imam told me a story that really took me aback. He said that a girl came to him because she was thinking of going to join ISIS. And I was really surprised and asked him, had she been in contact with a radical religious leader? And he said the problem was quite the opposite, that every cleric that she had talked to had shut her down and said that her rage, her sense of injustice in the world, was just going to get her in trouble. And so with nowhere to channel and make sense of this anger, she was a prime target to be exploited by extremists promising her a solution. What this imam did was to connect her back to God and to her community. He didn't shame her for her rage -- instead, he gave her constructive ways to make real change in the world. What she learned at that mosque prevented her from going to join ISIS. I've told you a little bit about how Islamophobia affects me and my family. But how does it impact ordinary Americans? How does it impact everyone else? How does consuming fear 24 hours a day affect the health of our democracy, the health of our free thought? Well, one study -- actually, several studies in neuroscience -- show that when we're afraid, at least three things happen. We become more accepting of authoritarianism, conformity and prejudice. One study showed that when subjects were exposed to news stories that were negative about Muslims, they became more accepting of military attacks on Muslim countries and policies that curtail the rights of American Muslims. Now, this isn't just academic. When you look at when anti-Muslim sentiment spiked between 2001 and 2013, it happened three times, but it wasn't around terrorist attacks. It was in the run up to the Iraq War and during two election cycles. So Islamophobia isn't just the natural response to Muslim terrorism as I would have expected. It can actually be a tool of public manipulation, eroding the very foundation of a free society, which is rational and well-informed citizens. Muslims are like canaries in the coal mine. We might be the first to feel it, but the toxic air of fear is harming us all. (Applause) And assigning collective guilt isn't just about having to explain yourself all the time. Deah and his wife Yusor were a young married couple living in Chapel Hill, North Carolina, where they both went to school. Deah was an athlete. He was in dental school, talented, promising ... And his sister would tell me that he was the sweetest, most generous human being she knew. She was visiting him there and he showed her his resume, and she was amazed. She said, "When did my baby brother become such an accomplished young man?" Just a few weeks after Suzanne's visit to her brother and his new wife, their neighbor, Craig Stephen Hicks, murdered them, as well as Yusor's sister, Razan, who was visiting for the afternoon, in their apartment, execution style, after posting anti-Muslim statements on his Facebook page. He shot Deah eight times. So bigotry isn't just immoral, it can even be lethal. So, back to my story. What happened after 9/11? Did we go to the mosque or did we play it safe and stay home? Well, we talked it over, and it might seem like a small decision, but to us, it was about what kind of America we wanted to leave for our kids: one that would control us by fear or one where we were practicing our religion freely. So we decided to go to the mosque. And we put my son in his car seat, buckled him in, and we drove silently, intensely, to the mosque. I took him out, I took off my shoes, I walked into the prayer hall and what I saw made me stop. The place was completely full. And then the imam made an announcement, thanking and welcoming our guests, because half the congregation were Christians, Jews, Buddhists, atheists, people of faith and no faith, who had come not to attack us, but to stand in solidarity with us. (Applause) I just break down at this time. These people were there because they chose courage and compassion over panic and prejudice. What will you choose? What will you choose at this time of fear and bigotry? Will you play it safe? Or will you join those who say we are better than that? Thank you. (Applause) Thank you so much. Helen Walters: So Dalia, you seem to have struck a chord. But I wonder, what would you say to those who might argue that you're giving a TED Talk, you're clearly a deep thinker, you work at a fancy think tank, you're an exception, you're not the rule. What would you say to those people? Dalia Mogahed: I would say, don't let this stage distract you, I'm completely ordinary. I'm not an exception. My story is not unusual. I am as ordinary as they come. When you look at Muslims around the world -- and I've done this, I've done the largest study ever done on Muslims around the world -- people want ordinary things. They want prosperity for their family, they want jobs and they want to live in peace. So I am not in any way an exception. When you meet people who seem like an exception to the rule, oftentimes it's that the rule is broken, not that they're an exception to it. HW: Thank you so much. Dalia Mogahed. (Applause)
¿Que soy una mujer de fe, una experta? Tal vez una hermana, o una mujer oprimida, a la que han lavado el cerebro. Una terrorista. O un retraso en la cola de seguridad del aeropuerto. Esto último es cierto. (Risas) Si su percepción ha sido negativa, no los culpo. Es la forma en que los medios han retratado a gente como yo. Un estudio observó que el 80 % de las noticias sobre el Islam y los musulmanes son negativas. Hay estudios que muestran que la mayoría en EE.UU. no conoce a un musulmán. Supongo que la gente no le habla a su taxista. (Risas) Bueno, para quienes no conocen a un musulmán, encantada de conocerlos. Les contaré quién soy. Soy madre y me encanta el café. Doble expreso, crema aparte. Soy introvertida. Me encanta estar en forma. Y soy practicante espiritual musulmana. Pero no como en la canción de Lady Gaga, porque no nací así. Para mí fue una opción. A los 17, decidí salir del armario. No como gay, como algunos de mis amigos, sino como musulmana. Y decidí ponerme la hijab, cubriendo mi cabeza. Mis amigas feministas se horrorizaron. ¿Por qué oprimirte? Lo curioso es que para mí, fue en ese momento una declaración feminista de independencia, de la opresión que sentía a mis 17 años, para ajustarme a los cánones inalcanzables de perfección y belleza. No acepté pasivamente la fe de mis padres. Luché contra el Corán. Leí y reflexioné, cuestioné y puse en duda, y en última instancia, creí. Mi relación con Dios no fue amor a primera vista. Fue una entrega confiada y lenta, que se fue profundizando con cada lectura del Corán. Su belleza rítmica, a veces me emociona. Me veo a mí misma en él. Siento que Dios me conoce. ¿Alguna vez han sentido como si alguien los viera y comprendiera por completo? ¿Y que los ama igualmente? Así me siento. Y más adelante me casé. Y como buena egipcia, empecé mi carrera como ingeniera. (Risas) Tuve un hijo después de casarme. En resumen, vivía el sueño egipcio-estadounidense. Hasta esa terrible mañana de septiembre de 2001. La mayoría seguramente recuerda exactamente dónde estaba esa mañana. Yo estaba sentada en la cocina, terminando el desayuno. Miré la pantalla del televisor, y vi las noticias. Había humo, aviones que se estrellaban en los edificios, gente que saltaba de los mismos. ¿Qué era todo eso? ¿Un accidente? ¿Algo funcionó mal? Pasé rápidamente del shock a la indignación. ¿Quién haría algo así? Cambio de canal y oigo: "...terrorista musulmán", "...en nombre del Islam", "...descendiente de Oriente Medio", "...yihad", "...deberíamos bombardear La Meca". Dios mío. No tan solo habían atacado a mi país, sino que, en un instante, las acciones de otra persona, me convertían de ciudadana en sospechosa. Ese mismo día tuvimos que conducir, por el centro de Estados Unidos, mudarnos a una nueva ciudad, para empezar la escuela. Y recuerdo estar sentada, en el asiento del copiloto, mientras conducíamos en silencio, agachada lo máximo posible. Por primera vez, tuve miedo de que alguien supiera que era musulmana. Nos mudamos a nuestro apartamento esa misma noche en una nueva ciudad, en lo que parecía un mundo totalmente diferente. Y entonces escuchaba, y veía y leía, las advertencias de las organizaciones nacionales musulmanas, avisando cosas como: "Esté alerta", "Tenga cuidado", "Permanezca en zonas iluminadas", "No se congregue". Me quedé en casa toda la semana. Y entonces fue viernes de esa semana, el día que los musulmanes se congregan para rezar. Y otra vez las advertencias: "No vaya este primer viernes, podría ser un objetivo". Y miraba las noticias, todas las noticias. Las emociones estaban a flor de piel, lo cual es comprensible, y también oía sobre los ataques a musulmanes, o gente que parecía ser musulmana a la que golpeaban en plena calle. Las mezquitas eran bombardeadas. Y pensé, mejor quedarse en casa. Aún así, algo no parecía estar bien. Porque los que atacaron nuestro país, atacaron nuestro país. Entiendo que la gente estuviese enojada con los terroristas. ¿Saben qué? Yo también. Y tener que justificarse todo el tiempo no es fácil. No me importan las preguntas. Me encantan las preguntas. Son las acusaciones las que se hacen duras. Hoy oímos decir a la gente cosas como: "Hay un problema en este país y se llama musulmanes. ¿Cuándo vamos a deshacernos de ellos?" Algunos quieren prohibir a los musulmanes y cerrar las mezquitas. Hablan de mi comunidad como si fuera un tumor en el cuerpo de EE.UU. Y mi única pregunta es: ¿Somos malignos o benignos? Ya saben, un tumor maligno, se extrae en su totalidad, y un tumor benigno se monitoriza. Este tipo de elección no tiene sentido, porque la pregunta es errónea. Los musulmanes, como los demás ciudadanos no son un tumor en el cuerpo de EE.UU., somos un órgano vital. (Aplausos) Gracias. Los musulmanes son inventores y profesores, socorristas y atletas olímpicos. ¿En serio cerrar las mezquitas hará que Estados Unidos sea más seguro? Podrá liberar algunas plazas de parking, pero no acabará con el terrorismo. Ir a la mezquita regularmente está asociado con tener una visión más tolerante de las personas de distinta fe y con un mayor compromiso cívico. Y como un jefe de policía en la zona de Washington DC me dijo recientemente, la gente no se radicaliza en las mezquitas. Se radicaliza en su sótano o habitación, delante de un computador. Y lo que uno encuentra sobre el proceso de radicalización es que empieza en línea, pero lo primero que pasa es que se le corta a la persona los vínculos con su comunidad, hasta con su familia, para que el grupo extremista pueda lavarle el cerebro, y hacerle creer que los terroristas son los verdaderos musulmanes, y que cualquiera que adore su comportamiento e ideología es un fuera de serie y un apóstata. Si queremos prevenir la radicalización, tenemos que asegurar que la gente vaya a la mezquita. Algunos argumentan que el Islam es una religión violenta. Después de todo, un grupo como ISIS basa su brutalidad en el Corán. Ahora como musulmana y madre, como ser humano, creo que debemos hacer todo lo posible para detener a un grupo como ISIS. Pero nos estaríamos dejando engañar por su discurso, si los consideramos representantes de una fe de 1600 millones de personas. (Aplausos) Gracias. ISIS tiene tanto que ver con el islamismo como el Ku Klux Klan con el cristianismo. (Aplausos) Los dos grupos afirman que su ideología se basa en su libro sagrado. Pero cuando los ves, no están motivados por lo que han leído en su libro sagrado. Es la brutalidad la que hace que lean estas cosas en la escritura. Recientemente, un imam prominente me contó una historia que me sorprendió. Me dijo que una chica se le acercó, porque estaba pensando en unirse a ISIS. Me sorprendió mucho y le pregunté si ella había estado en contacto con algún líder radical religioso. Y él respondió que el problema era más bien lo contrario, que cada clérigo con el que había hablado le había dado la espalda y dijo que su ira, su sentido de injusticia en el mundo, le iba a traer problemas. Sin manera de canalizar y dar sentido a su ira, se convertía en un objetivo prioritario a explotar por extremistas que le prometían una solución. El imam la conectó de nuevo con Dios y con su comunidad. No la avergonzó de su ira sino que le brindó formas constructivas de hacer un cambio real en el mundo. Lo que aprendió en esta mezquita, la salvó de unirse a ISIS. Les he contado un poco como la islamofobia me afecta a mí y a mi familia. Pero ¿cómo impacta a cualquier estadounidense? ¿Cómo impacta a todos los demás? ¿Cómo consumir miedo 24 horas al día afecta a la salud de nuestra democracia? ¿Y a la salud de nuestro libre pensamiento? Bueno un estudio, en realidad varios estudios en neurociencia, muestran que cuando tenemos miedo, al menos suceden 3 cosas: Somos más propicios a aceptar el autoritarismo, la conformidad y el prejuicio. Un estudio mostró que cuando los sujetos se exponían a nuevas historias negativas sobre musulmanes, eran más propicios a aceptar ataques militares en países musulmanes, y políticas que limiten los derechos de los musulmanes estadounidenses. Esto no es académico. Si uno analiza cuándo empezó el sentimiento anti-musulmán, entre 2001 y 2013, pasó tres veces, pero no cuando ocurrieron los ataques terroristas. Fue en el periodo previo a la guerra de Irak, y durante dos ciclos electorales. La islamofobia no es solo la respuesta natural al terrorismo musulmán, como era de esperar. Puede ser una herramienta de manipulación pública, que erosiona las bases de una sociedad libre, que son los ciudadanos racionales bien informados. Los musulmanes son como canarios en las minas de carbón. Seremos los primeros en sentirlo, pero el aire tóxico del miedo nos está perjudicando a todos. (Aplausos) Y asignar una culpa colectiva, no implica solo justificarse uno mismo todo el tiempo. Deah y su mujer Yusor eran una joven pareja de recién casados que vivían en Chapel Hill en Carolina del Norte, donde los dos fueron a la escuela. Deah era atleta. Iba a un colegio de dentistas, tenía talento, prometía... Y su hermana me decía que era el más dulce, el ser humano más generoso que ella había conocido. Ella estaba de visita y él le enseñó su curriculum; y se quedó impresionada. Dijo: "¿Cómo mi hermano pequeño se volvió un joven tan prometedor?" Tan solo unas semanas más tarde de visitar a su hermano y a su mujer, su vecino, Craig Stephen Hicks, los asesinó, así como a la hermana de Yusor, Razan, que estaba de visita esa tarde, en su apartamento, una ejecución, después de publicar declaraciones antimusulmanas en su Facebook. Disparó a Deah ocho veces. El fanatismo no es solo inmoral, puede ser letal. Pero volviendo a mi historia. ¿Que pasó después del 11-S? ¿Seguimos yendo a la mezquita o nos mantuvimos a salvo en casa? Bueno lo hablamos, y parecerá una decisión insignificante pero para nosotros se trataba de qué tipo de EE.UU. queríamos para nuestros hijos: uno que nos controla por miedo o uno donde podíamos practicar nuestra religión libremente. Por lo que decidimos ir a la mezquita. Y pusimos a mi hijo en el asiento del auto, le atamos el cinturón y en silencio, condujimos intensamente a la mezquita. Lo saqué del auto, me quité los zapatos, y anduve hasta la sala de oraciones. Y lo que vi me detuvo. El sitio estaba abarrotado. Y el imam se dirigió a la multitud dando la bienvenida y las gracias, porque la mitad de la congregación eran cristianos, judíos, budistas, ateos, gente de fe y sin fe, que habían venido no a atacarnos, sino a apoyarnos de forma solidaria. (Aplausos) En ese momento me emocioné. Estaban ahí porque eligieron el valor y la compasión sobre el pánico y el prejuicio. ¿Qué elegirían Uds.? ¿Qué elegirían en esos momentos de miedo y fanatismo? ¿Se mantendrían a salvo? ¿O se unirían a los que dicen que somos mejor que todo eso? Gracias. (Aplausos) Muchas gracias. Helen Walters: Dalia nos has tocado la fibra sensible. Pero me pregunto, ¿qué le dirías a los que argumentan que estás dando esta charla TED, que está claro que eres una persona de pensamiento profundo, que trabajas en un prestigioso laboratorio de ideas, que eres una excepción no la norma? ¿Qué le dirías a esa gente? Dalia Mogahed: Les diría no dejen que el escenario los distraiga, soy totalmente común. No soy una excepción. Mi historia no es inusual. Soy tan común como cualquiera. Cuando uno ve a los musulmanes en el mundo, y es lo que he hecho, el estudio más amplio que se haya realizado sobre los musulmanes en el mundo, la gente quiere cosas comunes. Prosperidad para su familia, un trabajo, y vivir en paz. Por lo que no soy ninguna excepción. Cuando encuentras gente que parece la excepción, muchas veces es la norma la que se ha roto, y no es que sean la excepción. HW: Muchas gracias, Dalia Mogahed. (Aplausos)